伙计啊
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa! Hey, pal,
你不能从这儿走
You can't cut through here.
-私人领地  -抱歉
- It's private property. - Sorry about that.
天呐
Oh, my god.
卡塞尔
Oh, Castle,
真希望我们一早上都能这样
I wish we could stay like this all morning.
是啊
Yeah.
还可以换其他体位
Among other positions.
你知道我最喜欢的体位是什么吗
Do you know what my favorite position is?
面对面
In person.
是啊  我也是
Yeah, mine, too.
这样吧  我周末可以飞过去啊
You know what? Maybe I can fly up this weekend
-如果没案子的话  -那我一定让你不虚此行
- if there's no new cases. - I would so make it worth your while.
不要啊  是办公室来的
Oh, no. It's the office.
我得去了
I have to call in.
周末计划泡汤了
And there goes our weekend tryst.
别急啊  或许不是有案子呢
No, maybe not. Maybe it's not a case.
永远都是有案子
Oh, it's always a case.
对了  你上班之前
Hey, maybe, uh, don't you want to take
不去冲个澡吗
a quick shower before work?
或许你可以把手机也带上
Maybe you could take the phone in with you.
毕竟是防水的嘛
It is waterproof.
晚点的吧
Maybe later.
我记着了
I'll hold you to that.
好
Okay.
派
Pi.
早啊  老爸
Morning, dad!
我和派没吵醒你吧
I hope Pi and I didn't wake you.
我们在做冰沙
We're making smoothies.
对我来说不那么好
And yet for me, not so smooth.
我也给你做一杯吧
I'll whip one up for you.
-大家早上好啊  -早
- Good morning, all! - Good morning.
派  我还是老样子
Ah! Pi, I'll have my usual.
可以抗衰老
Anti-aging.
-没问题  R太太  -谢谢
- You got it, Mrs. R. - Thank you.
亲爱的  你就不能假装
Darling, couldn't you just pretend
被派的努力打动了吗
to appreciate Pi's efforts?
什么努力  我现在都不知道
What efforts? Half the time, I don't know
我闻到的是家里的新堆肥箱
if I'm smelling our new compost bin
还是我女儿志向腐烂的味道
or my daughter's rotting ambition.
理查德  她才19  那个男孩不过是...听我说
Oh, Richard, she's 19 years old, and that boy is just--look.
这挺好  她疯一次就没事了
It's good. She'll get it out of her system.
我只希望这个过程能快点结束
I just wish she would get it out of her system faster,
也让他离开我的家
and out of my house.
或许我该去表个态
Maybe I should just put my foot down,
让她明白我有多反对
show her my stern disapproval.
别这样  那只会引起阿丽克西斯的叛逆
Please. Alexis will just rebel,
她会更想跟他在一起
and she'll want to be with him even more.
-那我该表示认同吗  -不不
- So then I should approve? - No, no, no.
那会让他们稳定下来
That'll just cement the relationship.
她会跟他在沙发上睡了
She'll be sleeping on the couch with him.
那我要怎么办
So what am I supposed to do?
把甘蓝汁喝了
Drink your kale blast.
忍忍就过去了
And just ride it out, kiddo.
那是查理·雷诺兹吗
Is that Charlie Reynolds?
-大点声  -警方正在调查
- Turn that up. - ...police are currently investigating.
雷诺兹是名演员
Reynolds was an actor,
其代表作是90年代的喜剧
best known as the star of the '90s TV comedy
《跩哥不上学》
"2 Cool For School,"
他扮演了可爱的书呆子杜威·汉考克
where he played lovable nerd Dewey Hancock. Oh...
太可怕了
How awful.
我还在那部剧里客串过呢
I did a guest spot on that show.
那时多简单啊
That was a simpler time,
杜威的金句"哈巴  哈巴"
When Dewey's catchphrase, "Hubba, hubba,"
人人都在说
passed as sparkling dialogue.
令人震惊的是  他的尸体
In a bizarre twist, the body was found
被吊在一个起重机的钩子上
hanging from the hook of a construction crane.
太吓人了
Oh, gruesome.
你的"吓人"是"太棒了"的意思吧
Yes. If by "gruesome," you mean awesome.
瞧啊  那是埃斯波西托和莱恩
Look. That's Esposito and Ryan.
这正是我需要的
This is exactly what I need.
前童星插死在钩子上
Former child star literally getting the hook.
搬起石头砸自己的脚
Hoisted on his own petard.
就那么晾在那儿
Hung out to dry.
我懂了  你又开始双关了
Okay, I get it.
你看见了吗
Did you see that?
他居然没接
He just declined my call.
看来不止有查理被晾在那儿了
Looks like Charlie isn't the only one hung out to dry.
让让
Okay.
我...
Hey, I was--
抱歉
Uh, sorry.
只有纽约警察可以入内
Only N.Y.P.D. past this point.
你一定是新来的  其实我...
You must be new here. I'm actually--
我非常清楚你是哪位
I know exactly who you are.
但是我说了  只有纽约警察可以入内
Like I said, only N.Y.P.D. past this point.
这...就他
That's--th-there-- right there.
他们是我哥们  伙计们
Those are my people right here. Hey, guys--
-没事  苏利  交给我们  -好吧
- It's okay, Sully. We got it. - All right.
-谢了  -好啊  卡塞尔
- Thanks. - Hey, Castle.
那是谁啊
Who's that guy, right?
那位是格兰特·苏利文警探
Uh, that is detective Grant Sullivan.
我们虽然想念贝克特
As much as we miss Beckett,
-能有个新人呼来喝去总是好事  -谢了
- It's nice to have a new guy to boss around. - Thanks.
你跑来干什么
What you doing here, bro?
你要是接了我的电话不就知道了
Well, you would know if you would have answered my call.
我一定没听见响
I must not have heard it ring.
你拒接了  而且还直播了出来
You rejected it. On live television.
伙计们  我大人大量  不会计较这些
Look, guys, look, I am big enough to overlook that
我还是愿意帮助二位
and still offer to help you guys out.
-帮助我们  -这可是起大案啊
- Help us out? - This is a high-profile case,
我愿意让你们单独享受我
and I am willing to let you guys exclusively benefit
不拘一格的破案头脑
from my out-of-the-box crime-solving mind.
你又能得到什么
And what do you get?
逃脱公寓里坑爹的生活
Escape from the life at the loft.
抱歉  卡塞尔  如果盖茨知道了...
Ah. Sorry, Castle. If Gates were to find out...
-是啊  -她不会的  她不会知道的
- Yeah. - She won't! She won't find out.
我知道她...
I happen to know she's...
她去福罗里达州开会了
She's at a conference in Florida, so...
你们不会注意到我的存在的
You won't even know I'm here.
过气情景喜剧明星挂在钩子上
A washed-up sitcom star dangling from a hook?
还有比这更好的吗
Does it get any better?
我小时候还一直看这部剧呢
I grew up watching that show.
查理·雷诺兹是极度被低估的演员
Charlie Reynolds is highly underrated as an actor.
《跩哥不上学》是永恒的经典
"2 Cool For School" is a timeless gem.
这我深表怀疑  虽然我并没看过
I seriously doubt that. Not that I've ever watched it.
卡塞尔先生  你又回来了
Mr. Castle, you're back.
但是并不受欢迎
But not by popular demand.
见到你也很高兴  帕穆特
Good to see you, too, Perlmutter.
能确定死亡时间了吗
Do you have a time of death for us?
晚7点到凌晨2点之间
Uh, between 7:00 p.m. and 2:00 a.m.
死因不言而喻  他从屋顶坠落下来
The cause is obvious. He plummeted off the roof
插死在钩子上
and landed on the hook.
会是自杀吗
Possible suicide?
从起重机跟大楼之间的距离
Based on the crane's distance from the building
以及楼顶的打斗痕迹来看
and signs of struggle on the roof...
他是被人推下去的
He was pushed.
查理·雷诺兹为什么要跑到屋顶上去
What was Charlie Reynolds doing on the roof in the first place?
好问题
That's a good question.
这栋楼里有间公寓是他的  但他不住这儿
He actually owns an apartment in the building, but he wasn't living here.
这里都被拆得干干净净了
Every unit's been stripped down to the studs,
所以他住在一栋转租房里
so he was staying in a sublet.
他有什么亲人吗
Any family or next of kin?
在电视剧里有  但现实生活中就没有了
On the tv show, yes. In real life, not so much.
不管他在做什么
Well, whatever he was doing here,
我已经让警员在这一带排查
I've got unis canvassing to see if anyone saw
询问昨晚是否有人在这一带看到了他
him or anyone else last night in the area.
这是什么意思
I wonder what this means.
九位数
Nine digits.
鉴于他被人推下楼  摔在一个钩子上
Well, given he was pushed off a roof and landed on a hook,
那应该不是个幸运数字了
I'm saying that is not his lucky number.
苏利
Yo, Sully.
来了
Yeah?
查下这串数字跟被害人有什么联系
Check out this number and see how it connects with our victim,
然后追查一下他死之前都去过哪里
and let's start piecing together where he was before he wound up here.
这就去  我查了他的语音留言
I'm on it. In the meantime, I checked his voicemail,
他昨天收到一堆愤怒的留言
and he had a bunch of angry messages yesterday
是一个女人留的
from some chick.
说如果他不打回来  她就杀了他
Said she would kill him if he didn't call her back.
她忍受不了被忽视
Said she would not be ignored.
典型的疯狂前女友
Aha. A classic rabbit boiler.
跟踪狂  先生们  狂热粉丝
Stalker, gentlemen. An obsessed fan.
查清楚她是谁了吗
Do we know who the caller is?
我追踪了号码  显示出市中心的一个地址
Uh, I traced the number to an address downtown.
-名字叫  -杰拉尔丁·鲍奥斯
- Uh, name is, uh... - Geraldine Powers.
杰拉尔丁·鲍奥斯  是的
Ger-geraldine powers. Yeah.
我打赌她甚至还把他供了起来
I bet she even has a creepy shrine to him.
查理·雷诺兹不是我杀的
I did not kill Charlie Reynolds!
-但你曾威胁要杀了他  -不止一次
- But you did threaten to kill him. - Repeatedly.
你看起来也对他颇为迷恋
And you do seem to have more than a casual interest in him.
当然
Well, of course I do.
是我让他的节目长盛不衰
I'm the one who kept his show on the air
整整六季
for six seasons.
你在接受治疗吗
Are you taking any medication?
我没疯
I am not delusional.
我是查理的经纪人  傻瓜
I am Charlie's agent, nitwit.
他的经纪人
His agent?
是啊
Yeah.
得知噩耗后我一直在看这节目
I've been running the shows nonstop since I got the news.
1992年查理出演《跩哥不上学》时
I signed Charlie back in '92
我签下了他
when he was on "2 Cool For School."
我怎么办
What do I do?
放松  小妞喜欢神秘感
Play it cool. Chicks dig mystery.
-神秘  -她来了
- Mystery... - Oh, here she comes.
节目被砍后  电话不再响个不停
After the show was canceled, the phones stopped ringing.
大多数经纪人会抛弃他  而我呢
Most agents would have dumped his ass, but me?
我不离不弃
I stuck with him.
就是这里  这是创造历史的一幕
Oh, this is the scene! This is where history was made.
嗨  丽莎
Hey, Lisa...
哈巴  哈巴
Hubba, hubba!
永恒的经典  不是吧你
A timeless gem? Really?
那是很精准的表演
Eh... that was a very... nuanced performance.
你说的都不足以解释
Nothing you're telling me is explaining
你为何要威胁查理·雷诺兹
why you threatened Charlie Reynolds.
查理的公寓重新装修期间
Charlie moved into a sublet
他搬进了一间转租的房子
while his building was being rehabbed.
几天前  他的几封信
And a few days ago, some of his mail
被错误地寄到了这里
got forwarded here by mistake.
他的银行账户显示他刚存了
His bank statement showed that he had just made a deposit
125000元
for 125 grand.
我为查理提供的工作
Charlie could barely cover his rent
仅供他支付房租
with the jobs I booked.
那么  这现金是从哪来的
So... where'd he get the cash?
唯一合理的解释是他背着我
Only thing that makes sense is that he booked a gig
接了别的活  把我的佣金占为己有
on the side and cut me out of my commission.
你知道是什么活吗
Do you have any idea what that gig was?
不  但他能存这么多钱
No, but... for him to pull in that kind of money...
这活一定不错
it had to be something big.
问题是这个神秘的工作
The key here is that mystery gig.
一个过气  勉强度日的演员
A down-on-his-luck actor barely scraping by?
也许他卷入了什么阴谋
Maybe he got involved in some shady deal
不幸丧命
that cost him his life.
或是有人赏识他的演技
Or someone recognized his true acting talent
给了他一份工作
and gave him a job.
那个充斥三流明星的《他们在哪儿》真人秀
Like some c-list "Where Are They Now?" reality show
他必须和丹尼·布纳德斯还有韦布斯特打架
where he has to mud-wrestle Danny Bonaduce and Webster
才能和唐纳德·特朗普一起工作
just to get a job with Donald Trump.
贝克特的桌子这是怎么了
What happened to Beckett's desk?
现在是苏利的桌子了
That's Sully's desk now.
卡塞尔先生
Oh, uh, Mr. Castle,
抱歉在现场时我有些冒犯
sorry if I came on a little strong back at the scene.
我还在努力融入这里
I'm still trying to get the lay of the land here.
接贝克特探长的班可不容易
Detective Beckett left some big shoes to fill.
确实  不过你倒是成功地把她的桌子堆满了
Yeah, she did. I see you filled her desk.
卡塞尔先生  你在这里做什么
Mr. Castle, what are you doing here?
盖茨警监  我
Captain Gates, I'm--I-I--
我以为你去开会了
I-I thought you were at a conference.
提前一天结束了
It ended a day early.
你肯定是查看了我的行程
But you wouldn't even know that
不然你是不会知道的
unless you were checking up on me.
我明白这是怎么回事了
Oh. I see what's happened here.
他厚着脸皮回来
This man has insinuated himself
就是为了调查查理·雷诺兹的案子  是吧
into the Charlie Reynolds investigation, hasn't he?
你们还同意了
And you let him.
告诉你  卡塞尔先生
Well, news for you, Mr. Castle.
你不属于纽约警察局
You are not N.Y.P.D.
没有理由再留下来
And you no longer have a reason for being here.
这是我们负责的谋杀案
This is our murder case.
不再是了
Not anymore.
-贝克特  -现在归我们负责了
- Beckett. - This is our case now.
这有一封司法部长的信
I have a letter from the attorney general
授权我们接管这个案件
authorizing our taking point on this case.
我能看一下吗
May I see that, please?
你来这里做什么
Wh-- what are you doing here?
我  我来干什么  你来干什么
Me? What am I doing--what are you doing here?
你怎么不告诉我你回纽约了
Why didn't you tell me you were coming to town?
本想给你个惊喜的
I was gonna surprise you.
真好
Well done.
那么就请你给我们简单介绍下情况吧
Then perhaps you should brief the team.
早上好  我是麦考德探员
Good morning. I am agent McCord.
你认识贝克特探员
Of course you know Agent Beckett.
我们要参与调查
We are joining this investigation,
需要知道与查理·雷诺兹死亡
so we need access to all information
相关的一切信息
regarding Charlie Reynolds' death.
按照调查局的说法  这是你们挤兑我们
Which is Feds speak for you're pushing us out.
不  你们继续调查
No, you'll continue to work the case.
只不过要向我们汇报
You'll just be reporting to us.
为什么一个前情景喜剧演员的谋杀案
Uh, why is the murder of an ex-sitcom star
会成为联邦案件
a federal case?
我们不便透露
We're not at liberty to say.
等等  让我把话说明白
No--wait, let me get this straight.
你想让我们继续调查
You want us to continue investigating,
向你们报告所有情况
report everything to you,
你们却不告知来这里的原因
but you're not going to tell us why you're here?
需者方知
It's need-to-know.
我们要借用一下会议室
We'll be setting up in the conference room.
我们需要所有的初步报告
We'll need any preliminary reports
以及雷诺兹的个人电子产品
and all of Reynolds' personal electronics--
手机  平板电脑和电脑
phones, iPads, computers.
感谢你们的合作
Thank you for your cooperation.
我们要用死者的手机和电脑数据
We'll use the victim's phone and computer data
重建他死前二十四小时
to reconstruct what he was up to
都做了什么
in his last 24 hours.
特区说得很清楚
And by the way, D.C. made it clear
调查结果要发给他们
that they want us to send it to them.
他们要这些数据做什么
Why do they want the data?
没说  一贯如此
They didn't say. They rarely do.
这一定让你很困扰吧
That's got to bother you.
我们不可能知道所有事
We don't always get the whole picture.
在特区工作就这样
Comes with the territory.
我们是不是该过去
Maybe we should go over there and just
请她们喝杯咖啡
invite 'em in for some coffee, you know?
才不要
We are not serving them coffee.
这咖啡机是你买给纽约警察局的
You bought this espresso machine for the N.Y.P.D.
-只能给纽约警局的人喝  -拜托  伙计们
- This is N.Y.P.D. coffee only. - Come on, guys.
-这有点过分了  -过分
- That's a little harsh. - Harsh?
贝克特是犹大
Beckett's a judas.
她和她搭档抢了我们的案子
Her and her partner just hijacked our case.
你是哪边的
Whose side are you on?
这边  当然是你们这边的
Your side. Guys, I'm... I'm on your side.
莱恩  是不是有点奇怪
Hey, Ryan, isn't it a little weird
卡塞尔出现的同一天
that Castle shows up the same day
贝克特探员就来了
that Agent Beckett takes over?
是啊  真巧合
Yes. It's quite a coincidence.
不  不是巧合
No. It's not. It's not a coincide--that--
是  不  还真是个巧合
Yeah, well... no, actually, yes, it's a coincidence.
没准你和贝克特是一伙的
Maybe you and Beckett are in on this together.
-没准  -什么
- Maybe... - What?
你是她的内应
You are her inside man.
你是犹大的犹大
You... are judas' judas.
不  伙计们  我发
No--guys--no, I swe--
我发誓  咱们认识这么久了
I swear. Come on. You know me.
我会盯着你的 卡塞尔
I'm watching you, Castle.
帕穆特说有发现了
Perlmutter's got something for us.
-我们走  -好
- Let's go. - Yeah.
经过仔细检查  我把死亡时间区
After a complete examination, I was able to narrow
缩为11:30到1:30之间
time of death to between 11:30 and 1:30.
手臂和肩膀上的死前淤青
And... perimortem bruising on the arm and shoulder
表明有搏斗的迹象
is consistent with signs of a struggle.
查理被推下去之前有过抵抗
So Charlie fought back before he was thrown off the roof?
对  但是
Yes. But...
最有趣的发现在这里
the most fascinating discovery resides in here.
这是
Which is?
我从被害人的鞋底取出来的
An unusually large quantity
新鲜鸟粪
of fresh bird excrement that I extracted
粪量异常的大
from the tread of the victim's shoes.
不用了  我相信你
Uh, no... I'll take your word for it.
他进过鸽子...
Okay, so he stepped in some pigeon--
对  只不过这不是鸽子粪
Sure. Only it didn't come from pigeons.
仔细分析之后发现
A painstaking analysis proves
这其实是鸡屎
that this is none other than chicken poop.
在曼哈顿很不常见
Not a lot of that in Manhattan.
也许查理的秘密工作和鸡有关
Maybe Charlie's mystery job had something to do with chickens?
《跩哥不上学》那种烂剧之后
Well, after "2 Cool For School,"
干什么都是一种进步啊
almost anything is a step up.
-喂  -还有什么发现
- Now-- - What else you got for us?
目前  我只有权利说这么多
I'm afraid that's all I'm authorized to tell you at this time.
我简直不敢相信
I can't believe it.
连帕穆特都得听联调局的
Even Perlmutter's answering to the Feds now.
我们在自己的案子上被架空了
We're being iced out of our own case.
也许她们保密
Guys, maybe there's a perfectly reasonable explanation
是有合理的原因的
for all this secrecy.
你们说的对
That's-- you... guys are right.
这真令人发指
This is outrageous!
苏利  查理的秘密工作有线索了吗
Hey, yo, Sully, any leads on Charlie's mystery job?
没有可以解释那125000美金的
Nothing that explains that 125 grand.
我目前查到的唯一线索是
The only thing I've been able to dig up so far
在过去几年间
is some personal appearance trips to Russia
他去过几次俄国
over the last few years.
俄国
Russia?
《跩哥不上学》在那边很火
Oh, yeah. "2 Cool For School" is huge over there.
杜威在俄国就像大卫·哈塞尔霍夫在德国
Dewey is to Russia what David Hasselhoff is to Germany.
我还在他信用卡上有所发现
Oh, I-I did catch a break off his credit card.
他出事那天
I got a line on a cab
有辆出租车去接过他
that picked Charlie up the day he got killed.
送他去哪里
Where'd it take him?
他的转租房  关键在于
His sublet. But here's the kicker.
另外一个人也上了车
Another dude hopped in the backseat,
他俩打了起来
and the two of them got in a huge fight.
有相貌描述吗
Did you get a description?
没有  有更好的  知道名字
Uh, no. Better. I got a name.
是他以前的合作演员  雷蒙·罗素
His former co-star Ramon Russo.
对  他演体优生马克
Oh, yeah. He played the Jock Marco, right?
原来你也看过
So... you have seen the show.
就是偶尔看过一眼
Just caught it by accident once. It was...
那也许你知道
Oh. Well, then as you might know,
不仅雷蒙演过马克  还有传言说
not only did Ramon play Marco, but word is,
他们憎恨对方
they hated each other.
也许就是不和才导致了谋杀
Maybe that feud led to murder.
那是个意外
It was an accident.
我本来想走的  但是他先推了我
I tried to walk away, but he pushed me first.
我不想杀他的  我发誓
I didn't mean to kill him, I swear.
雷蒙·罗素
Ramon Russo?
抱歉了  大伙儿
My apologies, you guys.
跟你们说  这种事经常有
I'm telling you, this happens to me all the time,
不管是我在外面
whether I'm out there on the street,
还是在这里上课
or here teaching class.
有什么事吗
So, how can I help you fellas?
你们是想要签名照片还是什么
You want a... an autographed picture, what?
借用你一些时间如何
How about some of your time?
可能要几十年
Maybe even decades of it.
查理的死  对我个人来说是个悲剧
I'm telling you, Charlie's death is a personal tragedy for me
也是演员界的巨大损失
and a huge loss for the acting community,
我会尽一切所能帮助你们
and I'll do anything I can to help you find
抓住凶手
whoever did this to him.
我们了解到你昨天和他一同搭坐出租车
We understand you shared a cab ride with him yesterday.
是的  我们一起收工
That's right. We... we left work together.
你和他一起工作
Oh. You worked with him?
干什么  和鸡有关吗
On what? And did it involve chickens?
鸡  不是  我们在拍《跩哥不上学》
Chickens? No! we were doing "2 Cool For School."
但那部剧已经停播20年了
But that show's been off the air for 20 years.
不是  我们在拍重聚电影
No, man. We're doing a reunion movie.
真的吗
You are?
这还是我们第一次听说
I mean, this is just the first we're hearing of it.
拍摄是保密的  我们都签了
It's on the down-low. You know, we all had to sign
那种保密协议
those confidentiality agreements.
实话实说
But to be honest...
我本来有很多其他剧
I had a lot of other projects in the works.
是查理求我来拍的
Charlie begged me to do it.
他说  我们这些兄弟
He said, you know, it'd be fun
再聚在一起会很有趣的
to get the old gang back together, you know?
即便你们两个不和吗
Even with all the bad blood between you two?
你的角色马克
I mean, wasn't your character-- Marco--
最开始的设定不是主演吗
originally supposed to be the star of the show?
杜威火了  抢了风头
And then Dewey caught fire, stole the spotlight.
抢了你的风头
Stole your spotlight.
我们那时候还小
We were kids back then.
那部剧让我们都受益良多
I mean, that show did a lot of great things for all of us.
不管我们有什么矛盾
Whatever issues we had,
我们很久之前就冰释前嫌了
we buried the hatchet a long time ago.
你的出租车司机可不是这么说的
Not according to your cabbie.
他说你们两个打起来了
He said the two of you got into a big fight.
是  我生气了  因为他在浪费我的时间
Yeah, I lost my temper because he was wasting my time.
他消极怠工
He was disrespecting the craft.
查理记不住台词
Charlie didn't know any of the lines.
他以前从不这样
I mean, I'm telling you, he was never like that.
他一向
He was--he was always real good
很擅长记台词什么的
with that kind of stuff, you know?
你是说查理有心事
You're saying there was something going on with Charlie.
绝对有
Definitely.
两三天前开始的
It started a couple days ago.
他开始变得很焦虑  很疲倦
He started showing up anxious and tired.
我问过他怎么了  他不肯说
And I asked him what was wrong, but he wouldn't say.
昨晚11:30到1:30你在哪里
Where were you last night between 11:30 and 1:30?
雷蒙的女朋友亚斯明证实了他的话
So Ramon's girlfriend Yasmine confirms the story.
他昨晚一直在家和她对台词
He was home all nights running lines with her.
比如说"我是这里最牛逼的人"
Lines like, "I'm the biggest deal to ever walk these halls."
雷蒙给了我一份签名的剧本
Ramon slipped me a signed copy of the script--
《跩哥不上学: 一事无成去教书》
"2 Cool For School--- Those Who Can't, Teach."
真的吗  情节是什么
Really? Well--well, what's the storyline?
杜威和马克回到湾景高中当老师
Dewey and Marco are back at Bayview High as faculty.
杜威是聪明的科学老师
Dewey is the brainy science teacher,
马克重拾光辉岁月当了橄榄球教练
While Marco is reliving his glory days as the football coach.
不  当杜威在休息室
Oh, no. When Dewey runs into
遇见性感的德语老师
the sexy German teacher-- Mrs. Pozman--
波兹曼夫人时  他说
in the break room, he says...
-哈巴  哈巴  -哈巴  哈巴
- "Hubba, hubba." - "Hubba, hubba."
哈巴  哈巴
"Hubba, Hubba."
我和片场的工作人员谈过了
Anyway, I, uh, talked to the office staff at the movie set,
查理不仅最近表现得很怪
and not only has Charlie been acting weird lately,
而且两天前  他哄着会计
but two days ago, he sweet-talked the accountant
让他看了账本
into letting him look over the books.
明星为什么在乎剧组预算呢
Why would the star care about the budget of the show?
不知道  不过会计说
I don't know, but the accountant told me
查理发现了不合法的地方
that Charlie said he'd found irregularities.
听好了  他逼她发誓
And get this. He made her swear
不能告诉制片人汉克·哈勃
not to tell the film's producer Hank Harper
他四处打听  查探
that he'd been poking around.
汉克·哈勃  我听过这个人
Hank Harper? I've heard of him.
有传言说他拿球棍
Rumor was he chased a director off set
追打过一个导演
with a baseball bat.
看这个  虽然罪名从未成立过
Check this out. Though he's never been convicted,
但汉克·哈勃面临着
Hank Harper has faced numerous charges of
多起挪用公款的控诉
embezzling money
都来自他经手的电影
from the films that he's worked on.
如果查理发现汉克
If Charlie would have found out that Hank
在挪用电影经费
was skimming money from the movie...
也许汉克解雇了查理[给了他一钩子]
Then maybe Hank gave Charlie the hook.
制作办公室的人说
According to the production office,
汉克·哈勃在片场的某个地方
Hank Harper's somewhere here on this set.
主角都死了他们怎么还在拍
What could they even be filming if the star is dead?
可能是没有杜威的戏份
Probably the scenes without Dewey.
或是解释他为什么没出现的戏份
Or scenes that explain why he's not in the whole movie.
或是他死而复生
Or he's back from the dead.
僵尸末日版  那我可要看一看了
The Zombie Apocalypse version. Now that I would watch.
你看
No, look, right there.
还有一个
There's another one.
他们肯定是在重新选角
They must be re-casting the part.
搞什么  杜威·汉考克是独一无二的
What? There's only one Dewey Hancock.
是吗  跟他去说
Yeah? Tell him that.
开拍
Action!
杜威  谢谢你腾出周五晚
Dewey, thanks for giving up a friday night
陪我监管舞会
to chaperone the dance with me.
到时候见
I'll see you there.
哈巴  哈巴
Hubba, hubba.
不不不
No, no, no!
"哈巴  哈巴"不仅仅是一句口头禅
"hubba, hubba" is not just a catchphrase,
它是这个角色的精髓
It is the essence of your character.
"哈巴  哈巴"发自内心  而不是用大脑
"hubba, hubba" comes from here, not here.
斯维特拉娜  让他找到"哈巴  哈巴"的感觉
And, Svetlana, make him work for the "hubba, hubba."
不不
No! No!
算了吧  拜托  你已经问过了
Forget it. Please. Come on. You tried this before.
-不行  -汉克·哈勃
- The answer's no. - Hank Harper.
你来晚了  帅哥
It's too late, pretty boy.
肌肉男体育老师的角色已经选定了
We already cast the muscular P.E. teacher.
纽约警局
N.Y.P.D.
我们是为了查理·雷诺兹的死来的
We're here about Charlie Reynolds.
我再联系你
I'm gonna have to call you back.
查理是个好孩子  行家里手
Charlie was a great kid, a real pro.
跟他共事让我回忆起跟帕西诺共事的时光
Working with him reminded me of the pictures I did with Pacino.
你跟阿尔·帕西诺共事过
You worked with Al Pacino?
巴里·帕西诺  不过毫无关系
Barry Pacino. No relation.
一样有本事  长得还更高
Every bit as talented, and taller.
既然你对查理的评价这么高
If you have such a high opinion of Charlie,
为什么找人替换他
how come you're already replacing him?
你们得明白
Look, you gotta understand,
利益攸关
there's a lot of money at stake here.
演出必须继续
The show must go on.
我也经历过
Ah! I've been there.
我的小说《妮基·希特》几年前拍成电影了
My book "Nikki Heat" got made into a movie a few years back.
不是直接发行DVD了吗
Didn't that go straight to DVD?
剧本有些问题
There were script issues.
还有...选角问题和导演问题
And... casting issues and directing issues.
查理跟片场工作人员有冲突吗
Did Charlie have any problems with anyone on set?
据我所知没有
Not that I'm aware of.
人人都喜欢他  没理由不喜欢啊
Everybody loved him. What's not to love?
他最近查看了会计账簿
He took a look at the accounting books recently.
知道为什么吗
Any idea why?
猜不出来  喂喂
Can't imagine. Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa.
-小心点  -我们知道
- Easy. - Well, we might.
也许是查理认为有人中饱私囊
Maybe Charlie thought somebody was skimming money.
我们听说你喜欢做假账
Yes, we heard about your penchant for creative bookkeeping.
慢着  你们以为我杀了他
Wait. You think I killed him?
如果查理发现你故技重施
Well, if Charlie found out that you were up to your old tricks,
这就是杀人动机
it would be motive.
首先  我整晚都在这里改剧本
First of all, I was here all night doing script changes.
再说以前的话我可能稍微揩点油
Plus I may have been caught with my hand in the cookie jar in the past,
但现在我不会那么傻
but I'm not stupid enough
去从俄国佬手里偷钱
to steal from the Russians.
俄国佬
The Russians?
是啊  是他们投资的
Yeah, they're financing this picture.
他们想把它做成系列电影
They want to make this into a franchise.
这可是我的饭票
This is my meal ticket!
所以如果账簿有哪里不妥的
So if there's anything hinky with the books,
跟我无关
it's not 'cause of me.
我们不会相信你的一面之辞
Yeah, well, we're not gonna take your word for that.
我们要看看账簿
We're gonna need to see those books.
好吧
Oh, oh, yeah.
都给你们
They're all yours.
谢谢
Thanks.
我们还要一顶帽子
We're gonna need one of these hats, too.
我有一点不明白
You know what I don't get?
你戴着那顶帽子  不明白的东西多了
You're wearing that hat. There's a lot you don't get.
假设汉克真的挪用了公款
Let's say Hank did embezzle money
然后杀了查理封口
and killed Charlie to silence him.
联调局怎么牵扯进来了
Why are the feds involved?
可能跟俄国佬有关系
Maybe it has something to do with the Russians.
如果我们掌握了联调局的切入点
Well, if we knew the feds' angle,
就能占据先机了
we'd have a leg up on solving this.
不好意思  我还没想出
Sorry, guys, I have yet to come up with
疯狂超赞的想法
a crazy genius... theories yet.
不需要
You don't need to,
你可以直接接触消息源头
not when you can go directly to the source.
让贝克特告诉我们内幕
Get Beckett to give us the lowdown.
等一下
Okay, wait a minute--
我们得到急需的案件资料
We get much-needed case information,
你能解决纠结不清的忠诚问题
you get to clear up any lingering doubts about your loyalty.
双赢
Everybody wins.
好吧  伙计们  我不能这么做
Okay, guys, no, I can't do that, all right?
特区那事之后  我们保证不
After D.C., we promised we wouldn't--
我们帮你争取到参与这个案子  卡塞尔
We did you a solid getting you on this case, Castle.
这人情是时候还了
It's time to pay up.
伙计们
Guys...
她是我未婚妻
This is my fiancee.
好吗  如果我频频越界
Okay? What does it say about our future
会影响我们的未来啊
if I keep pushing the boundaries?
卡塞尔  你们的关系就建立在
Castle, your whole relationship is built
你各种越界之上
on a foundation of your boundary pushing.
说得好
Good point.
收到你的短信了
I got your text.
我就是想跟你见见面
I just wanted to check in with you.
换了身份
You know, it must be weird for you
回到局里办案
being back here at the precinct,
-很怪吧  -是啊
- working a case. - Yeah. Yeah, it is.
特别是自从麦考德下达禁言令
Yeah. Especially since Mccord's little gag order
不让你接近
prevents you from accessing
最得力的破案工具
your most effective investigative tool...
我
Me.
好吧  你是工具[混蛋]
Yeah, you are a tool, all right?
那么
So, uh...
趁她现在不在
She's not here right now,
透点消息给我没什么大碍吧
so what's the harm in giving me a little tidbit?
你这是在行贿
This is a bribe.
卡塞尔  你用一杯拿铁向我行贿
Castle, you're bribing me with a latte?
没有  我没有
No, I am not.
得了  别说笑了
Come on. Don't be ridiculous.
太下作了  即使是对你来说
This is low, even for you.
听着  我能解决这个案子
Look, I can solve this.
只是需要更多信息接着查
I just need a little more to go on.
卡塞尔
Castle...
你别跟我来这套
You're not gonna Castle me on this one.
她过来了
Okay, she's coming.
如果跟俄国佬有关就点一下头
Just nod once if it's about the Russians,
如果关于其他事就点两下头
twice if it's about something else.
两下  是关于其他事
Twice. About something else.
三下  那是
Three times. What's--
那是...什么意思
What does th-- what does that mean?
什么...为什么...我不明白
What--how come-- I don't know what that means.
有线索  我们走
We got a lead. Let's go.
再见啦  卡塞尔
See you, Castle.
点三下头是什么意思
What does th-- what does three nods mean?
如何
Well?
我试过了  但是...
I tried, but...
她不肯告诉我案子的事
She won't talk to me about the case.
那她们两个要去哪
Well, where did the two of them go just now?
她也没告诉我
Yeah, she wouldn't tell me that, either.
我只是
Hey, I was just--
我现在不想理你
I can't even look at you right now.
伙计们  我们找到一些
Hey, guys, I think we found something
查理所看账簿上的线索
in these books Charlie was looking into.
我都看过了
I went over them, and there's no signs
没有商业诈骗的迹象
of any financial shenanigans.
资产负债表看上去很干净  但是
The balance sheet seems kosher, but, um,
看看这个分类账条目
check out this ledger entry.
这个数字跟查理口袋里找到的一样
That is the number we found in Charlie's pocket.
这就是查理口中的异常部分
This must be that irregularity that Charlie was talking about.
但这是什么意思呢
But what does it mean?
这是从俄罗斯运来的
Well, it corresponds to an invoice number
电影摄像设备的
for a shipment of camera equipment for the movie
发票号码
sent over from Russia.
这有什么异常的
What makes that an irregularity?
首先  在这里租摄像机
Well, for one thing, it'd be a lot cheaper
便宜多了
just to rent cameras here.
不仅如此
Not only that,
货物还运到了布鲁克林的一家仓库
but the shipment was sent to a warehouse in Brooklyn...
隔壁正好是一家鸡加工厂
which happens to be right next to a chicken processing plant.
这就解释了查理鞋上的粪便了
Which explains the poop on Charlie's shoes.
查理被杀之前去了那间仓库
Charlie went to that warehouse right before he was killed.
也许凶手也去了那
Maybe whoever killed him came from there.
看起来是个废弃仓库
Looks deserted.
是  但并不代表真的被废弃了
Yeah, that doesn't mean that it is.
这里可能涌现一大群残忍的哥萨克人
This place could be teeming with bloodthirsty cossacks.
-你还有枪吗  -没你的份
- Do you have an extra gun? - Not for you.
至少我们来对地方了
At least we know we're in the right place.
我肯定踩到了什么东西
I definitely stepped in something.
伙计们  我找到了
Hey, guys, I found it.
我找到了货物  一样的发票号
I found the shipment. Same invoice number.
只是一些摄像器材
It is just camera gear.
等等  这是个假底
Wait a minute. It's a false bottom.
好的
All right.
我妈总说电影生意很难做
My mother always said that the film business was tough.
这就是为什么俄罗斯人为这部愚蠢的电影筹资
That's why the Russians are financing that dumbass movie.
他们利用拍电影走私非法武器
They're using the production to smuggle in illegal weapons.
就像《逃离德黑兰》  只是换成了枪
It's like "Argo," but with guns.
放下枪  双手举起来
Put the gun down and show me your hands!
现在慢慢转身
Now turn around slowly.
你们在这干什么
What the hell are you guys doing here?
我们找到了你们在找的枪
We're finding the guns you're looking for.
什么枪
What guns?
你们不知道枪的事吗
You didn't know about the guns?
我们此行是为了观察和汇报
We came here to observe and report.
关于这件案子我们没你们知道的多
We don't know any more about this case than you do.
那你们怎么会到这
Well, then how did you guys get here?
通过重现被害人的行踪
By retracing our victim's movements.
他被杀那天来过这
He came here the day he died.
他肯定是无意间发现这些枪
He must have come across these guns.
我会联系烟草火器与爆炸物管理局保护这些武器
I'll contact the A.T.F., have them secure the weapons.
别这么快  克拉丽斯
Not so fast, Clarice.
这是我们找到的
We're the ones who found 'em,
所以纽约警察会把这些归为证据
So N.Y.P.D.'s gonna be the one booking these into evidence.
你们都错了
That's where you're both wrong!
这些枪哪也不会去
These guns aren't going anywhere.
放下你的武器
Put your weapon down now.
你是那个慢跑者 发现尸体的人
You're the jogger. The guy who found the body.
放下枪  我们是联邦探员
Just put the gun down. We're federal agents.
我也是
I'm a federal agent, too.
我叫伊森·怀特  中情局的人
Name's Ethan Wright. I'm C.I.A.
让拉丁壮男打个电话  一切就清楚了
Have Mario Lopez here make the call.
就算你说的一切属实
Assuming you are who you say you are,
中情局为什么牵涉其中呢
why would the C.I.A. be involved?
查理·雷诺兹在为我们做事
Charlie Reynolds was working for us.
两年前我雇了他
I recruited him two years ago.
杜威是个间谍
Dewey was a spy?
我们利用他渗入安东·伦科夫家族
We used him to infiltrate the family of Anton Renkov.
安东·伦科夫  我听说过
Anton Renkov? I know that name.
在俄罗斯他是臭名远昭的黑帮老大
He's the most notorious gangster in all Russia.
他也是《跩哥不上学》的狂热粉丝
He's also a major fan of "2 Cool For School."
那就是为什么查理去俄罗斯的原因
That's why Charlie was taking all those trips to Russia.
没错  那里的人喜欢他
That's right. They love him there,
所以我找到他  希望利用他
So I approached him about using those trips
收集伦科夫及他的黑帮组织的情报
to gather intel on Renkov and his organization.
查理毫不犹豫答应了  他是个好人
Charlie didn't hesitate. He was good.
事实上他的演技
Turned out he was a better actor
比大部分人想的要好
than most people gave him credit for.
我就是这个意思
That's what I've been saying.
这家伙身份核实了
Yo. This guy checks out.
谢天谢地  胳膊快麻了
Thank god. My arm.
这么说安东·伦科夫利用这部电影
So Anton Renkov was using the movie
做为幌子为俄罗斯黑帮
as a front to smuggle arms into the U.S.
走私武器进美国
for the Russian mob.
而查理的任务就是找到这些枪
And Charlie's job was to find those guns.
差不多是这样
More or less.
几天前他联系了我
He contacted me a couple of days ago.
告诉我他已经找到了货物
He told me that he'd located the shipment.
我们安排了会面  打算给他一个GPS追踪器
We set up a meet so we could get him a G.P.S. tracker
安防在枪支上
to attach to the guns.
他没打电话给我  我开始找他
When he didn't call, I started looking for him.
你可以早点告诉我们的
Would have been nice if you told us sooner.
怎么说呢  需者方知
What can I say? It was need-to-know.
我们需要你监控这次调查
We needed you to monitor the investigation
以防纽约警察惊动俄罗斯人
So N.Y.P.D. didn't get too close to the Russians
从而损害我们的行动
to compromise our operation.
我们也想到你们会指引我们找到军火
We also figured you might lead us to the weapons,
你们真的找到了
which you did.
那现在怎么办
So... what happens now?
我们希望伦科夫拿走这些枪
We hope that Renkov sends the guns on
不论这些枪去往何地
to wherever they're going...
我们就可以追踪它们
So we can track them.
而你们可以走了
And you guys walk away.
不敢相信查理被派去
I can't believe Charlie was spying
安东·伦科夫和黑帮组织身边做间谍
on Anton Renkov and his organization.
-有没有哪个熟面孔  -有
- Any of them look familiar? - Yeah.
我看到三个俄罗斯人出现在电影片场
I saw about three of those Russians on the movie set.
根据国际刑警那边的资料
Mm-hmm. And according to interpol,
他们在本国都有犯罪记录
all of them got criminal records back in the motherland--
袭击  谋杀  坏事做尽
Assault, murder, all kinds of bad stuff.
我猜他们其中一个发现了查理是个间谍
I bet one of them found out that Charlie was a spy,
然后杀了他
and they killed him.
尤其当我们知道
Especially since we know that Charlie
查理去仓库的时候被跟踪
was followed to the warehouse.
基于什么
Based on what?
我们通过查理的手机信号
We tracked Charlie's movements
三角定位追踪查理的行踪
by triangulating the cell towers that his phone pinged off,
之后我们用时间标志
and then we used that time stamp
拿到了仓库的卫星录像
to pull satellite footage of the warehouse.
你们怎么找到那的
How'd you guys get there?
鸡粪
Chicken poop.
不管怎么找到的
Well, whatever works.
我们知道有人跟踪他
We knew someone was following him.
这就是调查的方向
That's what I'd investigate.
事实上  我们要暂停调查了
Actually, we need to hit pause on the investigation.
特区那边下通知了
Word just came down from D.C.
为什么
Why?
中情局不相信伦科夫知道查理是间谍
C.I.A. doesn't believe Renkov knows Charlie was a mole.
他们认为俄罗斯人会转移那些武器
They think the Russians would have moved the weapons
如果他们知道的话
If they knew.
我们对那些武器没兴趣
Well, we're not interested in the weapons.
我们只是想破谋杀案
We just want to solve his murder.
特区对此也有问题
And D.C. Has a problem with that.
你们跟俄罗斯人谈话  会打草惊蛇
You talk to these Russians, it could kick up some dust,
引起他们对查理·雷诺兹的警觉
set off their alarms about Charlie Reynolds
这会影响中情局的行动
and jeopardize the C.I.A. operation.
那你的暂停调查意思就是停止调查
Okay. So by "pause," what you really mean is "stop."
我知道你的感受
I know how you feel,
但这个案子牵涉到国家安全
but this case intersects with national security issues.
我很抱歉  但一切都结束了
I'm sorry, but it's over.
收到你的短信了  你几点的飞机
Got your text. What time's your flight?
明天早上
Tomorrow morning.
听着
So listen.
关于收买你那件事我很抱歉
I'm, uh, sorry about that whole bribe thing.
我早该清楚你是清廉的
I should have known you were incorruptible.
我可不这么认为
Yeah, I wouldn't say that.
那么  允许我试着带坏你
Well, then allow me to try and corrupt you
待会儿在我家
A little later at my place,
我们终于可以二人世界
Where we can finally have some alone time.
我说的二人世界  指的是你和我
And by "alone time," I mean you and me and...
还有我妈和阿莱克西斯还有...派
My mother and Alexis and... Pi.
这个
That...
听起来有点挤
That sounds... crowded.
是的
Yeah.
等你们破了这个案子
You know what? Why don't you just give me a call
给我打个电话
after you guys have solved the case?
你没听麦考德说的吗  案子结束了
Didn't you hear McCord? The case is wrapped.
是吗
Is it?
"牺牲小我"什么的最操蛋
This whole "greater good" thing blows.
查理是为国牺牲的
Charlie died serving his country.
他应该得到公道
He deserves justice.
贝克特怎么了  她以前明白这个道理的
What happened to Beckett? She used to understand that.
我认为她依旧明白
I think she still does.
这个应该就是贝克特所说的
This must be the satellite footage
卫星摄像
Beckett was talking about.
这里拍到查理走进仓库
And there's Charlie entering the warehouse.
先生们
Uh, gentlemen?
我猜你们是在处理那个已经结束调查的
I take it you're finishing up paperwork on the case
案子的文书工作
that you are no longer investigating?
-没错  -是的  头  -必须的
- You bet. - Yes, sir. - Absolutely.
很好  继续吧
Good. Carry on.
看到这个人了吗
Okay. You see him?
贝克特说的没错  查理被人跟踪了
Beckett was right. Charlie was followed.
而且他还带着棒球帽做伪装
And look, he's wearing a baseball cap to be incognito.
隐藏得不够深呀  你看帽子上的图案
Not incognito enough. Check out the design on that hat.
就跟我拿的那顶
Just like the...
《跩哥不上学》的剧组帽子一样
"2 Cool For School" crew hat that I got.
那顶被你取笑的帽子
The one you made fun of.
所以跟踪查理的人是剧组里的人
So whoever followed Charlie came from the movie set.
谢谢
Thanks for your time.
伙计们  剧组上的人都说
Guys, nobody at the production office
没看到有人跟踪查理
saw Charlie being followed.
但是那天他录影一结束
But soon as he was done filming for the day,
就让私人助理开车送他去了布鲁克林的一个杂货铺
a P.A. gave him a ride to a bodega in Brooklyn.
那个杂货铺离仓库只有五个街区
That bodega -- five blocks from the warehouse.
这是杂货铺外面的摄像头的监控录像
This is the security cam footage from outside the bodega.
根据时间
And based on the time stamp,
私人助理正是这个时候把查理送到那
this is when the P.A. dropped Charlie off.
来了  是他
That's him. There he is.
好的
Okay...
接着
and...
之后就是戴帽子那家伙了
there's our guy in the crew hat.
看不清他的脸
I can't quite make out his face.
换个角度试试
Try a different angle.
我拉近画面试试
Ah, I'm gonna try zooming in.
那是电影里的女演员
That's the actress from the movie.
等一下  她不只是个演员
Wait a minute. She's not just an actress.
她还是斯维特拉娜·伦科夫
She's also Svetlana Renkov.
她是安东的侄女
She's Anton's niece.
哈巴  哈巴
Hubba, hubba.
也就是说你们的人做了
So basically your people did exactly
我明确说明不要做的事
what I told them not to do?
当你认为中情局的行动
You put us in a difficult spot when you decided
比破谋杀案更重要的那刻起
that the C.I.A.'s agenda was more important
我们就已经骑虎难下了
than solving a murder?
这不是我的决定  我也只是听命而行
I didn't decide anything. Orders came down.
这不是我第一次
This is not my first rodeo
对付华府来的人了
dealing with the folks down in D.C.
很快  对于你们来说
Soon enough,
查理·雷诺兹就消失在记忆的长河里了
the name "Charlie Reynolds" will be a distant memory for you.
但是我们则不会
But not for us.
也许他没有伤心欲绝的母亲
He may not have had a grieving mother
或是妻子在家等候
or a wife waiting for him,
但是他的凶手仍应得到惩罚
but his killer should not go unpunished.
不管怎么说
Regardless,
我都不能让你们去审问斯维特拉娜·伦科夫
I can't let you take a run at Svetlana Renkov.
中情局之所以停了这个案子
Look, the whole reason
就是因为他们坚信
the C.I.A. is shutting this case down
俄国佬还不知道
is because they are convinced that the Russians
查理是个间谍
didn't realize that Charlie was a spy.
但是安东的侄女在跟踪他
But Anton's niece following Charlie
这似乎跟他们的结论不符
seems to contradict that.
而且如果俄国佬真的盯上了查理
And if the Russians did get on to Charlie,
中情局应该也希望知道
wouldn't the C.I.A. want to know
他们的行动暴露了吧
that their mission is compromised?
好吧
Okay.
为了控制住局面
In the spirit of containment...
我们去找斯维特拉娜聊聊吧
let's talk to Svetlana.
你跟踪了他
You followed him.
你跟踪他到了仓库
You followed him to the warehouse.
是的
Yes.
他为什么要去仓库
Why did he go there?
他在找枪
He was looking for guns.
你也正是在那个时候意识到
And that was when you realized...
他要背叛你的家人
he was about to betray your family,
所以你就告密了
and so you told them.
我没告诉任何人
I told no one.
你甚至没告诉你的叔叔安东
You didn't even tell your uncle Anton
-或是其他亲戚吗  -没有
- or your other relatives? - No.
我知道查理是间谍
I knew Charlie was a spy,
但我从来没跟家人透露过
but I never said so to my family.
我宁愿先死
I would die first.
我和查理相爱了
We were in love.
抱歉  你说什么
I'm sorry. What?
我可以拿我们的情书给你看
I can show you our love letters.
你笑话杜威  可他不仅仅是秘密特工
You mock Dewey, but not only was he a secret agent,
还抱得美人归
look at that.
他风流倜傥
He was a stud.
这简直就是罗密欧与朱丽叶
It's Romeo and Juliet...
只不过罗密欧是个书呆子
with a nerdy Romeo.
而朱丽叶是个超级火辣的俄国妹
And a smokin'-hot Russian Juliet.
我们是一见钟情
We fell in love the moment we met.
两年来我只有在查理
For two years, I only saw Charlie
来俄国参加安东的派对时才有机会见他
when he came to Anton's parties in Russia.
他知道我想逃离
He knew I wanted to get away --
逃离那种生活
away from that life.
所以当安东投资这部电影时
So when Anton paid for the movie,
查理说这是我来美国
Charlie said it was a-a perfect chance
我们俩团聚的绝佳机会
for me to come here, for us to be together.
如果你说的都是事实的话
Okay, if all of that's true,
那你又为什么要跟踪他到仓库去呢
then why did you trail him to the warehouse?
我想求他不要去找那些枪
To beg him not to look for those guns.
我担心我的家人会发现
I was afraid my family would find out.
事实上呢
And did they?
没发现  不然的话我也死定了
No. If they knew, I would be dead, too.
我叫查理罢手  但他不肯听我的
I told him to stop, but Charlie wouldn't listen to me.
他说在我们消失之前
He said he had to finish this one last mission
他必须完成这个最后的任务
before we disappeared.
你说消失是什么意思
What do you mean, disappeared?
我们准备私奔然后重新开始
We were going to run away and start over.
我们原定在今天离开的
We were supposed to leave today,
逃离我的家庭  重新开始
get away from my family, get a fresh start.
查理想抛下过去的一切
Charlie wanted to leave everything behind --
间谍工作  演艺工作
the spying, the acting,
和杜威那个愚蠢的角色
the stupid character of Dewey.
那他的公寓呢  他可是刚花了一大笔钱
What about his apartment? He just spent a lot of money
重新装修呢
renovating it.
也不要了
He was leaving that, too.
他可能忍不住
I mean, he could have gone to the roof
想要再最后看一眼那个地方  道个别
for one last look at the place, say good-bye.
他用不着  他知道公寓会有人照顾的
He didn't have to. He knew it was in good hands.
他把它赠给了一个朋友
He was giving it to a friend.
所以他那晚才会在那
That's why he was there that night.
那位朋友是谁
Who's the friend?
这太难以置信了
I can't believe it.
真没想到是他
It's not who I would have expected.
他一直躲在我们眼皮底下
He was hiding in plain sight this whole time.
雷蒙
Ramon.
你被捕了
You're under arrest.
雷蒙你之前跟我们说
Now, Ramon, you told us
你除了这部电影外还有别的工作
that you had other projects in the works,
你说你接拍完全是为了查理
that you did the reunion move as a favor to Charlie.
看在旧情义的份上
For old times' sake.
朋友就该这样
That's what friends are for.
但我并不是个凶手
That doesn't make me a killer.
我们调查了一下
Yeah. Well, we looked into these, um,
你所谓的其它工作  我们发现
other projects, and, well, this is what we found.
你在东环球安保公司
You've been working the graveyard
当了四年的墓地看守员
at Global East Security for four years.
演艺事业嘛
Well, you know, acting has its, uh,
有起有落
ups and downs, you know?
我知道我会很快重回演艺圈的
I knew I'd get back in the game soon enough.
是啊  特别是当在《跩哥不上学》里
Yeah. Especially if playing the football coach
扮演足球教练
on "2 Cool For School"
成了稳定的工作
turned out to be a recurring gig.
本来是想拍续集的  但如果查理退出
Plan was to make sequels, but if Charlie bailed,
就拍不成了
there wouldn't be any.
你就又得回去当保安了
You'd be back to working security.
我没有伤害查理  我有不在场证明
I didn't hurt Charlie. I have an alibi.
现在没有了
Well, yeah... not anymore.
你看  你女友承认
See, your girlfriend admitted to us
她为你说了谎
that she lied for you.
她同时承认
She also mentioned that
那晚你借了他的信用卡
you borrowed her credit card that night.
我们发现你用那张卡消费了一趟出租车之旅
Yeah, it turns out that you used it to charge a cab ride...
去查理的住处
To Charlie's building.
你从未告诉我们查理打算让你
You never told us that Charlie was gonna let you
住他的公寓  因为你知道
stay at his apartment, because you knew
那会将你与犯罪现场联系起来
it connected you to the crime scene.
我可以解释清楚一下  好吗
I can explain, okay? I can explain everything, all right?
-都结束了  雷蒙  -不不  听着
- It's over, Ramon. - No, no, no, no, no. Look.
他拍了一场戏  之后他说他要离开
He was doing a scene, and after that, he told me he was leaving.
不是暂时离开
And I don't mean just for the day.
是再也不回来了
He was leaving for good.
他想重新开始
He wanted a fresh start.
他跟我一样没工作好久了
He had been out of work as long as me.
现在我们有机会拍电影
And now we had a shot at doing these movies.
不能就这样放弃机会
You don't walk away from that kind of opportunity,
不要这工钱
that kind of money!
你怎么会出现在房顶
How did you end up on the roof?
他约我在那见面
'cause he asked me to meet him there!
我以为他改变主意了  就去了
So I thought maybe he'd changed his mind, so I went.
我们站在那儿  看着风景
So there we were, looking at the great view.
他说我可以免费住在他的公寓
And he's saying to me that I can stay at his place for free.
我才不要他的怜悯
I don't want no charity!
我才不要给他看房子
I don't want to be house-sitting.
我想找回我的演艺事业  他毁了一切
I wanted my career back, and he ruined it!
于是你就发怒了
So you just snapped.
当我演那部剧时
You know, when I was on the show,
我有钱  姑娘  好车  名牌衣服
I had money--for girls, for cars, for clothes,
找啥有啥  突然  一切都没了
for whatever, and then, bam, all it's gone.
没有提醒你一无所有的感觉
And nobody tells you how it feels when it's gone, you know?
倒是有一帮人在你身边帮你花钱
Plenty of people around you to help you spend it, though.
我想回到那种生活
I just wanted my old life back.
我们拿到了完整的认罪
We're getting a full confession,
很大程度上  多亏了你
thanks to you, in large part.
别忘了我们  贝克特探员
Don't be a stranger, Agent Beckett.
有时间  回来看看
Drop by and see us sometime.
谢谢  长官  我会的
Thank you, sir. I will.
斯维特拉娜怎么还在
Why is Svetlana still here?
中情局要我们先扣留她
The C.I.A. asked us to hold her.
斯维特拉娜  这是你的机会
Svetlana, this is your opportunity
去缅怀查理
to honor Charlie's memory,
去完成他未完成的事业
to carry on his work.
你要我出卖我的家人
You are asking me to spy on my family?
你可以随意接触到
You have unprecedented access
安东·伦科夫和他的黑帮组织
to Anton Renkov and his organization.
这对我们来说十分重要
That is extremely valuable to us.
你知道如果他们发现了会对我做出什么吗
Do you know what they will do to me when they learn of this?
他们现在就能知道
They could learn of this right now.
如果查理是中情局特工的消息传出
If word somehow got out that Charlie was C.I.A.,
你的家人会问些让你头疼的问题
your family would ask some pretty tough questions.
你为什么要这样对我
You would do this to me?
你如果帮我们  我就不会
Not if you help us.
他在吓唬她
He's bluffing.
中情局不会那样暴露她的
C.I.A.'s not gonna just expose her like that.
那可不一定
Yeah, well, I wouldn't bet on it.
她爱的男人被谋杀了
The man that she loved was murdered,
他还让她去执行自杀行动
and he's gonna send her on a suicide mission?
如我所说
Like I said,
我们无法总是看到大局
we don't always see the whole picture.
这一个我觉得很清楚
I think this one's pretty clear.
不错
Yeah, looks good. You know?
苏利  老档案
Hey, yo, Sully, nostalgia file.
谢了  莱恩
Thanks, Ryan.
我要走了
I'm off.
-我来道个别  -见到你真好
- I just thought I'd say bye. - Good to see you.
是啊
Yeah.
你觉得麦考德会想念我们吗
You think McCord is gonna miss us?
会想死的
Oh, yeah, desperately,
但是我会帮忙让她恢复过来
but I'll be there to pick up the pieces.
那个中情局特工真的逼迫斯维特拉娜
Is that C.I.A. spook really forcing Svetlana
接查理的班了吗  太狠毒了
to take Charlie's place? That's not right.
是啊  不过你知道的  我们也无能为力
Yeah, but, you know, there's not much that we can do about it,
我会清理干净的  我发誓
I'm gonna clean that up, I swear.
不用
No. No.
现在这是你的桌子了
This is your desk now.
还有
And, uh...
在我看来  你很称职
from what I can tell, you earned it.
谢谢  这话对我来说意义重大
Well, thanks. That means a lot coming from you.
-警方逮捕了  -看看这个
- Police have arrested... - Check this out.
前《跩哥不上学》演员雷蒙·罗素
Former "2 Cool For School" star Ramon Russo
因谋杀查理·雷诺兹一案
for the murder of Charlie Reynolds.
知情人表示罗素的动机
Sources close to the case say Russo's motive
与雷诺兹与另一位主演
may be tied to Reynolds' relationship
斯维特拉娜·伦科夫的恋情有关
with co-star Svetlana Renkov,
她因与俄罗斯黑帮的联系
who is currently under investigation
正在被警方调查
for her alleged ties to russian organized crime.
他们怎么知道的
Whoa. Whoa. Where'd they get that?
斯维特拉娜没有被调查
Svetlana's not under investigation.
也有有人提供了不靠谱的消息
Maybe someone fed them a bad tip.
这事要是被她家人知道
You know, once that news hits her family,
他们会跟她撇清关系的
they're gonna cut ties with her.
她就对中情局没有价值了
She'll be no good to the C.I.A., huh?
真是糟糕
Too bad.
搞匿名爆料这一套
Playing the anonymous source card?
太机智了
I mean, that is pure genius. It...
让我更爱你了
It actually makes me love you more.
她在申请庇护
Well, she's filing for asylum,
国务院会帮忙
and the state department is gonna help
给她找个新地方
relocate her, so...
希望那样能保证她安全
Hopefully that'll keep her safe.
是啊  即便是给调查局工作
Yeah, but even working for the feds, you--
你还是找到了方法帮助被害人
you found the ultimate way to honor the victim.
查理拼了命就是为了让斯维特拉娜
Charlie died trying to get Svetlana away
远离她危险的家人
from her dangerous family.
你完成了他的任务
You completed his mission.
是的  但你也会这么做的  卡塞尔
Yeah, but you would have done the same thing, Castle.
是的  我会因我那样做更爱我
Yes. Yes, and I would love me more for doing it, too.
听着
Listen.
我们得谈谈这件事
We really have to talk about something.
好
Okay.
我们异地恋
We've been doing this long-distance thing
好几个月了
for months, and, uh...
我是说我们总是见不到面
I mean, we never see each other,
就算见到了  也只是一天
and when we do, it's a-- it's a day here,
或是一个周末
It's a-a weekend there, and...
面对现实吧   这样不行
let's face it, I-it's not... working.
我知道  卡塞尔
I... I know, Castle,
但我不知道怎么解决这件事
But I don't-- i don't know how to f-fix this.
我知道
I do.
这是什么
What is that?
是一把钥匙
Well, it's a key...
我们特区公寓的钥匙
To our D.C. apartment.
我是说  其实
I mean, the truth is, I can--
我在哪儿都可以写书  于是我就找到一个住处
I can write from anywhere, so I found a place
有个小小的工作室
with a little home office.
如果你到时候不喜欢
Listen, if you don't like it when you see it, we can--
我不用看  我非常喜欢
No. I don't need to see it. I love this.
稍等
Hold that thought. Okay.
我给母亲  阿丽克西斯和派买了过夜的瑜伽之旅
I bought mother, Alexis, and Pi a overnight yoga retreat.
他们不会这么早回来
They should not be home early.
我以为我们的航班明早8点才起飞
Hey. I thought our flight was at 8:00 in the morning.
是的
It is.
他们知道是你给媒体走漏了风声
They know it was you that tipped off the press.
我呢  很敬佩你的选择
A part of me really admires you for the choice that you made,
因为我希望当时
Maybe because I'd like to think there was a time
我也能像你一样有这样的勇气和正义感
that I would have done it.
但是我们的上司不这么想
But the people we answer to don't feel that way.
蕾切尔  我
Rachel, I-I--
凯特  你是我合作过最棒的探员
Kate, you're one of the best agents I've ever worked with.
但是我是来通知你  你被解雇了
But I'm here to tell you you're fired.